mynycb.com 2010-11-26

# WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT YOUR PRIVACY

        WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW ABOUT YOUR PRIVACY
Privacy Protection of Personal Information
Protecting the privacy and confidentiality of our customers’ personal information is of utmost importance to New York
Community Bancorp, Inc. and its family of companies, including:
•    New York Community Bank and its divisions;
•    New York Commercial Bank and its division;
•    NYCB Mortgage Company, LLC (a subsidiary of New York Community Bank);
•    CFS Investments, Inc. (a subsidiary of New York Community Bank); and
•    Standard Funding Corp. (a subsidiary of New York Commercial Bank).
(Each and all of the above companies are individually and collectively referred to as “NYCB”, “our”, “us” or “we” in
this notice.)
We value your business and the trust you put in us. To assist us in providing you the quality services and products that
you request or to help meet your needs, we gather, maintain and use both public and nonpublic personal information
about you on a routine basis. To assist you better in understanding how we use your personal information, we are
providing you with the following statement describing our policies and practices with respect to the sharing of
customer information. If your customer relationship with us terminates, or if you become an inactive customer, our
privacy policy will continue to apply to you.
This policy applies to information we receive, collect, or disclose in connection with products and services you request
or obtain for personal, family or household purposes. This policy does not apply to information we receive, collect, or
disclose in connection with products and services you request or obtain for business or commercial purposes.
What Information Do We Collect?
We collect nonpublic personal information about you from the following sources:
•    Information we receive from you on applications or other forms;
•    Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others; and
•    Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency.
“Nonpublic personal information” means personally identifiable financial and other related information that is not
available from public sources.
What Information Do We Disclose?
We may disclose all of the information that we collect, as described above, which includes, but is not limited to, the
following kinds of nonpublic personal information:
•    Information we receive from you on applications or other forms; such as your name, address, social security
     number, assets and income;
•    Information about your transactions with us (“Transaction Data”), or about your transactions with our affiliates or
     others; such as your account balance, payment history, parties to your transactions, and your credit and debit card
     usage; and
•    Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency or other sources (“Third Party Data”); such as your
     creditworthiness and credit history.
Rev. 09/20/2010                                              1

To Whom Do We Disclose Information?
We may disclose nonpublic personal information about you to affiliated and nonaffiliated third-party companies,
which might include financial service providers (such as securities broker-dealers and insurance agents), retail
businesses or direct marketers that we partner with, or other businesses that we believe can provide beneficial products
or services to you. We may also disclose nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties as
permitted or required by law. We may also disclose all of the information we collect, as described above, to companies
that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing
agreements.
Your Right to Opt-Out
If you prefer that we not disclose nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties, you may opt-
out of those disclosures, that is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures (other than those permitted or required
by law). If you wish to opt-out of disclosures to nonaffiliated third parties, you may call the following toll-free
numbers: 1-888-696-4444 for NYCB Mortgage Company, LLC and the AmTrust Bank and Ohio Saving Bank
divisions of New York Community Bank; 1-877-786-6560 for all other divisions of New York Community Bank,
1-800-535-2269 for New York Commercial Bank, or 1-800-526-2470 ext. 255 for Standard Funding Corp. Your
election to opt-out will apply to all nonpublic personal information we have about you relating to or arising from
products and services you request or obtain for personal, family or household purposes. If you have a joint account
with one or more other individuals, an opt-out election sent by any one individual will apply to all nonpublic personal
information we have about each of the owners of that joint account, relating to or arising from products and services
any of those owners requests or obtains for personal, family or household purposes. If you choose to opt-out you may
not receive certain information on products or services that may be of interest to you. The Fair Credit Reporting Act
also allows you to opt-out from NYCB sharing non-transaction or other information (such as consumer credit report
information) with affiliates. To opt-out please call the number(s) above.
Notice to Vermont Residents Only: You do not have to call us to opt-out of disclosures to nonaffiliated third parties if
(and while) you reside in Vermont. If (and while) you reside in Vermont, we will consider you to have automatically
opted-out from NYCB disclosing nonpublic personal information about you to nonaffiliated third parties, other than:
(1) those disclosures permitted or required by law; and (ii) other than disclosure of “Transaction Data” (as defined
above) to our service providers and our joint marketing partners.
If (and while) you reside in Vermont, we will only share “Transaction Data” (as defined above) with our service
providers, our joint marketing partners, and as otherwise required or permitted by law. Sharing of any “Third Party
Data” (as defined above) with nonaffiliated third parties will generally require your consent (unless such sharing is
otherwise required or permitted by law).
What Are Our Security Procedures?
We understand that the protection of your nonpublic personal information is of the utmost importance. We restrict
access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who have a business need to know the
information, such as to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural
safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information. Our employees are
educated on the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of customer information.
Rev. 09/20/2010                                              2

                                      Notice to California Customers
                                        Important Privacy Choices for Consumers
                    You have the right to control whether we share some of your personal information.
                   Please read the following information carefully before you make your choices below.
 Your Rights
 You have the following rights to restrict the sharing of personal and financial information with our affiliates (companies we own
 or control) and outside companies that we do business with. Nothing in this form prohibits the sharing of information necessary
 for us to follow the law, as permitted by law, or to give you the best service on your accounts with us. This includes sending you
 information about some other products or services.
 Your Choices
 Restrict Information Sharing With Companies We Own or Control (Affiliates): Unless you say “No,” we may share
 personal and financial information about you with our affiliated companies.
 [ ] NO, please do not share personal and financial information with your affiliated companies.
 Restrict Information Sharing With Other Companies We Do Business With To Provide Financial Products And
 Services: Unless you say “No,” we may share personal and financial information about you with outside companies we contract
 with to provide financial products and services to you.
 [ ] NO, please do not share personal and financial information with outside companies you contract with to provide financial
 products and services.
 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Time Sensitive Reply
 You may make your privacy choice(s) at any time. Your choice(s) marked here will remain unless you state otherwise.
 However, if we do not hear from you we may share some of your information with affiliated companies and other companies
 with whom we have contracts to provide products and services.
 To exercise your choices do the following:
 Fill out, sign and send back this form to us using the envelope provided (you may want to make a copy for your records).
 Name: ___________________________________________
 Account Number(s):_________________________________
 Signature: ________________________________________
Rev. 09/20/2010                                                              3

                (This page is intentionally left blank)
Rev. 09/20/2010                    4

                                                Marketing Opt-out Notice
•   The NYCB family of companies is providing this notice.
•   Federal law gives you the right to limit some but not all marketing from the NYCB companies. Federal law also
    requires us to give you this notice to tell you about your choice to limit marketing from the NYCB family of
    companies.
•   You may limit the NYCB Family of Companies, such as the New York Community Bank, New York Commercial
    Bank, NYCB Mortgage Company, LLC, CFS Investments, Inc. and Standard Funding Corp. affiliates, from
    marketing their products or services to you based on your personal information that they receive from other NYCB
    companies. This information includes your income, your account history, and your credit score.
•   Your choice to limit marketing offers from the NYCB companies will apply until you tell us to change your
    choice.
•   To limit marketing offers, contact us by telephone at:
    ¾ For NYCB Mortgage Company, LLC and the AmTrust Bank and Ohio Savings Bank
         divisions of New York Community Bank.................................................................................…1-888-696-4444
    ¾ For all other divisions of New York Community Bank….……………………………………...1-877-786-6560
    ¾ For New York Commercial Bank….……………………...…………………………………….1-800-535-2269
NOTE:         Please DO NOT fill out the form below for any of the divisions or affiliates of NYCB above, the form
              below is for Standard Funding Corp Opt Out ONLY.
 (cut along dotted line) - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
For Standard Funding Corp ONLY, check the box, complete the form, and send the form to:
                                                              Standard Funding Corp.
                                                             335 Crossways Park Drive
                                                           Woodbury, New York 11797
 Do not allow your affiliates to use my personal information to market to me.
Name: _________________________________________________________________________________________
Address: _______________________________________________________________________________________
Account Number(s): ______________________________________________________________________________
Signature: ______________________________________________________________________________________
Rev. 09/20/2010                                                                5
